Where's Xu Fengnian?
徐凤年呢
Senior,
前辈
please keep an eye on them.
帮我看住她们俩
Why are you still going out when badly wounded?
你都这样了还想出去
I have to go.
只能是我去
Uncle.
王叔
Where are your Buddha beads?
王叔的佛珠呢
Not wearing it?
没戴着
Are they all subordinates you have now?
这就是你的全部手下
May I have a word with you, Uncle?
王叔可否借一步说话
Follow up.
跟过来
Let me go with you, Your Highness.
我随世子过去
Stay here.
你们留下
I'll have a private talk with him.
我陪王叔单独聊
Wang Mingyin died?
王明寅死了
No.11 Swordsman is true to his name.
天下第十一名不虚传
Luckily, I have Li Chungang
幸好小侄身边
who could do Snakes in Sleeves.
有两袖青蛇的李淳罡
He's still alive?
剑神犹在
He's in my carriage.
就在方才那辆马车上
Then why did you still come with me?
那你还敢跟我过来
Why didn't I?
为何不呢
If you stayed around Li Chungang,
留在李淳罡身边
you might stay alive.
或许你还能保住这条小命
You don't want to kill me.
王叔又不杀我
What should I worry about?
我担心什么
If I don't want to kill you,
不杀你
why did I invite No.11 Swordsman?
我请来天下第十一做什么
If you wanted to kill me,
王叔若真要杀我的话
you could have used your army.
大军出击即可
Why did you bother to invite a swordsman?
何必请什么江湖人士
Then why do you think
那你觉得
I asked Wang Mingyin
我让王明寅刺杀你
to kill you?
是为什么
You arranged the assassination in the reeds
芦苇荡这场刺杀
to put up a show for someone.
是杀给别人看的
Who do you mean?
杀给谁看
Someone in the capital.
京城啊
The royal family.
皇室啊
North Liang is hard to control.
北椋尾大不掉
There's also a huge army in Qingzhou.
青州又何尝不是统领大军
They're both vassal towns.
都是藩镇
If you didn't assassinate me,
王叔若不刺杀我一场
you couldn't reassure the royal family.
离阳皇室怎么能对您放心呢
So, you also know
原来你也知道
Qingzhou and North Liang are bound to be enemies.
青州和北椋注定为敌
It's just the trend of times.
大势所趋罢了
The problem could have been easily solved.
原来呢 事情很简单
As long as you gave Wang Linquan to me,
你只要把王林泉交给我
you could have left Qingzhou.
你就可以离开青州
But now,
可现在
there's no turning back for neither you nor me.
你我都无路可退了
It's Xu Xiao's plan.
那是徐骁想的办法
I don't like it.
我不喜欢
So, I'll find a way out by myself.
所以我自己找生路
Do you mean
调戏本王王妃
flirting with my wife?
就是你找的生路
In Xiangfan
在欀樊
and even the entire Qingzhou,
乃至整个青州
everybody knows
人人皆知
that you love
王叔最宠爱的
your wife Pei Nanwei most.
就是王妃裴南苇
Everyone in Qingzhou knows
青州境内都知道
Lord of Jing'an treats Consort Pei Nanwei
靖安王将王妃裴南苇
as a treasure.
视作珍宝
Zhao Xun, son of Lord of Jing'an,
世子赵珣呢
once was obsessed with Pei Nanwei.
曾经痴迷裴南苇
Later,
后来呢
Lord of Jing'an married her.
被靖安王
After they got married,
成亲之后
His Lordship loved her a lot.
靖安王对王妃宠爱有加
Not only in Xiangfan,
但不仅仅是欀樊城
but also throughout Qingzhou,
整个青州
everyone knows
都知道王妃
Lord of Jing'an loves his wife most.
是靖安王最爱之人
But I...
而我呢
I've been thinking about something.
一直在想一个问题
What kind of man are you?
靖安王到底是怎样的人物啊
When lords were fighting for the throne,
当年众王夺嫡
you were the most scheming one.
王叔城府最深
Your own clique didn't show up
麾下嫡系不到最后时刻
until the last minute.
绝不显山露水
You were just unlucky
只是时运不济
so that you failed.
才失败罢了
It was a long time ago.
那都是很久以前的事了
What's the point of bringing it up?
有什么好说的
Why would such a scheming man like you
一个城府如此之深的人
let everybody in Qingzhou
怎么可能会让全青州
know your Achilles' heel?
都知道自己的弱点
If you really loved Pei Nanwei,
王叔若是真宠爱裴南苇
you would only keep her in your mansion
只会把她深藏府中
and let no one know about her.
绝不让人知晓
Don't you know who I am?
你们不知道我是谁吗
Back off!
退回去
Lord of Jing'an is quite generous.
靖安王好慷慨啊
He'll even let his wife die with us.
居然让自己的王妃跟我们陪葬
A man with an Achilles' heel
一个有弱点的人
will reassure others.
自然会让人放心
However,
只是
if we only focus on that,
只盯着表面上明显的弱点
we'll ignore the real danger.
会让人忽视真正的危险
Pei Nanwei is my Achilles' heel?
裴南苇是我的弱点
You make people think she's your Achilles' heel.
只是王爷自己造出来的弱点罢了
She's the scapegoat only.
推给人前看的
We're talking about whether I'll kill you.
现在聊的是杀不杀你
Aren't you getting off the subject?
你跑题了吧
The Achilles' heel you gave me
王叔送来的弱点
is the chance of my survival.
正是小侄的生路
You know it very well.
王叔其实心知肚明
This is the only good reason
亦只有一条可以光明正大的
for letting me leave Qingzhou.
放我离开青州的理由
Also,
而且
it won't make the court suspect you.
还不会招到朝堂猜忌
See the nephew off.
送侄千里
When I saw your message,
当我看到这四个字的时候
I explained to Pei Nanwei
我就和裴南苇说了
that there were two meanings
王叔的这句话
of the four words.
有两层意思
Two meanings?
两层意思
The first one is easy to understand.
第一层好解释
Off means down,
千里向下
namely the hell.
视为九泉
He wants to kill me.
王叔想要送我归西
The first meaning
第一层嘛
is for people in the world.
是给天下人看的
As I flirted with your wife,
我调戏王妃
you wanted to kill me.
惹来杀身之祸
What about the second meaning?
第二层意思呢
The second meaning...
这第二层意思
You're giving me a present.
王叔是在送礼
The present will accompany me
把礼物送给小侄
and see me off.
送至千里之外
What's the present?
礼物是什么
Pei Nanwei, of course.
那自然是裴南苇了
I'm giving my wife to you?
本王把自己的王妃送给你
This is the best reason
这才是王叔不杀我
for not killing me.
最好的理由
I'm lecherous and absurd.
小侄好色荒唐
And I'm daring.
胆大包天
I not only flirted with your wife,
不仅调戏王妃
but also kidnapped her.
还把人掠走了
In the end,
最后
I'll threaten you
以王妃性命
with her life.
要挟王爷
You don't have a choice,
王爷无奈
but to let me leave Qingzhou.
只能放我离开青州
What's better,
更妙的是
after you let me leave,
这一放之后
the court won't worry
朝堂绝对不会担忧
that you may ally with us secretly.
青州和北椋暗中联盟
After all, we're not going to make up
毕竟夺妻之恨
because I've taken away your wife.
绝无转圜余地
If I
若本王
really wanted to let you go,
真的想放你走
why did I arrange
又为何要闹这出
the assassination in the reeds?
芦苇荡刺杀呢
If you didn't,
不刺杀的话
the court wouldn't be relieved.
朝堂怎会安心
It's a fake assassination?
假刺杀
It's not.
刺杀不假
If I died,
我若真的死了
it would only mean
那就说明
I wasn't qualified to be your ally.
我没资格做王叔的盟友
Ally?
盟友
Under cover of the feud,
有深仇大恨作掩护
Qingzhou and North Liang
青州和北椋
may help each other
未来或可
in the future.
同舟共济
The premise is
前提是
that you become the Lord of North Liang.
等你继位北椋王
Don't you want to try
王叔就不想试试
fighting for the throne again?
再去争一争那位置
Xu Xiao...
徐骁
...has a good son.
生了一个好儿子
I saw what you did.
方才瞧见姑娘动手了
We both want to kill Xu Fengnian.
我们都要杀徐凤年
We can
可以
join hands.
联手合作
The gold is all mine.
一千两黄金都是我的
Get lost.
滚
Otherwise,
不然
I'll kill you.
杀了你
Go away.
滚
All right then.
好嘞
I'm going away.
那我就先滚了
Where's His Highness?
世子呢
I got the Book of Blade
这本刀谱
from Wudi City.
是本王从武帝城求来的
Now that you use blades,
既然你使刀
it will be helpful.
总会用得上
What's in the wooden box?
那这木盒呢
Half of Mumaniu.
里边是半柄木马牛
Li Chungang's sword?
李剑神的佩剑
Exactly.
正是
It was broken by Wang Xianzhi.
虽然被王仙芝折断了
But a broken sword
可就算是断剑
can still be of great use
在剑神手中
in the hands of God of Sword.
也是神物
You prepared it in advance.
提前准备
Did you know Li Chungang would travel with me?
您是早就知道李淳罡与我同行
I knew he was around you
就知道李淳罡在
so that I asked No.11 swordsman to assassinate you without concern.
才放心让天下第十一出手刺杀
The assassination had to be real.
刺杀就得真实
But I couldn't really kill you.
可是也不能让你脑袋真的搬了家
Otherwise, your crazy father
不然徐骁那个老疯子
would certainly start a war against me.
铁定马踏青州
I believe in Buddhism.
王叔我是想礼佛
But I don't want to die for that.
可没打算自己去西天极乐
Off you go.
你可以走了
One last question.
最后一个问题
Did you spend a thousand taels of gold
你是不是花了千两黄金
hiring a girl to kill me?
让一个女孩杀我
I did.
有这回事
Miss Hehe is an assassin you've trained?
呵呵姑娘是你训练出来的杀手
You've asked too many questions.
你问太多了
The last piece of advice for you.
最后一个忠告
Don't take Pei Nanwei to Wudi City.
不要带裴南苇去武帝城
She's fishy.
这个女人有问题
I suspected
我怀疑
that she approached my son deliberately.
她是故意接近我儿子
That's why
所以
I married her first!
我干脆先把她娶了
He left?
他走了
Yes.
没错
And he left you to me.
把你留下了
Don't you want to ask
你就不想问问
what I'm going to do with you?
我准备对你做什么
I have one question.
我倒是有一个问题
Speak.
你说
You had Wang Linquan sent away
你送走王林泉
and invited me to the reeds,
约我来芦苇荡
because you knew there would be an assassination?
是早就猜到有一场刺杀
I did know that.
是有准备
You let the Wang Family live.
你给了王家生路
But you had Fengzi Battalion take the risk for you.
可最后还不是让凤字营为你冒险
These soldiers
这些人
died for you.
全都是因你而死
Xu Fengnian,
徐凤年
you're quite hypocritical.
你的慈悲可真虚伪
Shut up!
放肆
It's different.
这不一样
What makes it different?
怎么不一样
A hundred soldiers of Fengzi Battalion left North Liang with me.
凤字营百人随我出北椋
We met Fujiang Armor in the rain.
雨中遇伏将红甲
Forty-five of them died.
战死四十五人
In the boat fight on Chunshen Lake,
春神湖船战
another two soldiers died.
又有二人牺牲
After today's battle,
今日一战
less than ten soldiers
所剩者
are still alive.
不足十人
Those who died in battles
这些战死者
are from North Liang
和王伯一家一样
just like the Wang Family.
都是我北椋子弟
But they have different identities.
但他们身份不同
The Wang Family
王伯一家
are ordinary people.
是普通人
Those in Fengzi Battalion
而凤字营
are soldiers!
是军人
A soldier's duty
军人的意义
is to protect ordinary people
就是用自己的血和剑
like the Wang Family
保护像王伯一家这样的普通人
with his blood and weapon!
平安无恙
I've kept in mind
所有的这些牺牲
those who died.
我记在心里
I feel sad.
我很难过
But if I were given a second chance,
但如果再来一次的话
I would make the same choice!
我还是会这么选
Because I couldn't escape.
因为我无法逃避
I wouldn't escape, either.
我也不会逃避
From first to last,
自始至终
I've been fighting with them
我徐凤年都和他们一起
shoulder by shoulder
并肩作战
and confronting the moment of death!
一同面对生死
Your Highness, it's our honor
能与世子并肩作战
to fight shoulder by shoulder with you.
是凤字营的荣耀
Your Highness.
世子
Qingniao hasn't woken up yet?
青鸟还没醒
She's in the other carriage. Someone's taking care of her.
人在那辆车上有人守着
Luckily, I completed the conversation.
幸亏我撑住了
If Lord of Jing'an realized I was badly wounded,
要是让靖安王看出我身受重伤
he might not let me leave safely.
还不一定能放我安全离开
You've made a good deal.
你倒是做了个好买卖
You planned
一早就想着
to kidnap Consort of Jing'an long ago.
劫走王妃
If Lord of Jing'an didn't give me a chance,
要不是靖安王给机会
he wouldn't ask Pei Nanwei
也不会让裴南苇
to bring a message to the weeds.
来芦苇荡送信
We just understood each other.
大家心照不宣罢了
You and that old fox understood each other?
你和那老狐狸心照不宣
You're birds of a feather.
一窝狐狸
He's an old fox.
他是狐狸
But I'm a young phoenix.
本世子是雏凤
You're both beasts, anyway.
反正都禽兽
You're getting more sharp-tongued.
你这话锋越发犀利了
Speaking of beasts,
说到禽兽
I think of something.
我想起个事
What is it?
什么事
Do you remember I saw a dead Hukui
还记得在清城山
on Mount Qingcheng?
遇到虎夔被杀
I got lost in the woods
那时候我在林里走散
and saw someone rush past, riding on a giant beast.
见到有人骑着巨兽呼啸而过
I wonder what killed Hukui.
也不知道是什么杀了虎夔
I saw that.
我看见了
It rushed past me.
从我跟前跑过去的
What did it look like?
长什么样
It was so fast that I didn't see it clearly.
跑太快没记清楚
It was black and white,
就记着黑白杂色
carrying a girl on its back.
而且背上还背了个人
When I think of it now,
现在想想那背影
the girl was like that assassin when looked from behind.
和刚才刺杀你的那个丫头特别像
Are you saying Miss Hehe killed Hukui?
你是说虎夔是呵呵姑娘杀的
Then she followed us as early as we were on Mount Qingcheng?
那她从清城山就跟着我们了
It doesn't make sense.
不对啊
We didn't arrive in Qingzhou at that time.
那个时候还没进青州城呢
Does she want to kill me
难道她不止是为了
not simply for the gold from Lord of Jing'an?
靖安王的千两黄金杀我
She lied to you.
她在骗你
Did she want to kill me
那她是在陵州城卖酱牛肉
even when she sold braised beef in Lingzhou?
就伺机想杀我
It doesn't make sense, either.
也不对啊
She could have assassinated me many times these years.
这么多年那么多机会
Why bother waiting until now?
干嘛等到现在才动手
What's your relationship
你到底跟那个什么
with Miss Hehe?
嘻嘻哈哈姑娘有什么关系
I met her several times when I did some beef shopping.
我就买肉的时候见过几次
I didn't even know her name.
我都不知道她名字
Because she kept smiling,
我看她整天笑呵呵的
I named her Miss Hehe.
给她起名叫呵呵姑娘
Also,
还有啊
Lord Jing'an reminded me.
靖安王提醒得对
Pei Nanwei can't go with us.
裴南苇不能跟我们同行
Care about yourself, first.
你先考虑考虑自己吧
Why?
我怎么了
Your eyes are bleeding.
你眼睛都在流血
Bleeding from all the seven openings of my head?
这便是七窍流血吗
I've heard about it.
听说过这词
Unexpectedly,
没想到有一天
I could experience it by myself.
自己亲身体验
If you keep experiencing it, you'll die.
再体验下去就得死了
Senior,
前辈
you mentioned the way to destroy my pubic region.
除了上次说的毁丹田
But is there an alternative?
还有什么生路
Yes.
有
Please instruct me.
请前辈明示
Digest the genuine spirit
消化真气
and you can live with a new body.
脱胎换骨就能活下去
A new body?
脱胎换骨
Hidden in your body,
大黄庭在你体内潜藏
Dahuangting goes into your passages as time goes by.
日积月累地慢慢融入经脉
It's a stable process, but it dissipates quickly, too.
虽然稳健可消散得也快
If it goes on like this,
本来按照这样下去
you'll digest 30% at most.
最后你能接受最多也就三成
But that girl badly wounded you
如今那个丫头将你重伤
and you've got a disorder in your body.
气息紊乱
If you can take the chance
如果你能够趁此机会
to digest Dahuangting forcibly,
强行吸收
you can absorb 50% at least
成功之后大黄庭
after you make it.
你起码能吸收五成以上
In this way,
这对你来说
you're kind of getting a new body.
就是脱胎换骨了
You mean I can survive
也就是说不但能活
and even get more power?
功力还能长
No, no, no.
不不不
When you digest it forcibly,
强行吸收是
you'll be rising from the dead.
置之死地而后生
The breakthrough in passages will be like thousands of cuts.
经脉冲破犹如千刀万剐
How long can you bear the pain?
那种痛你能熬多久
How long do I have to bear it?
需要挺多久
I'm not sure.
不知道需要多少时辰
In every moment of the process,
这期间每一刻
you'll feel like you're skinned.
都犹如身受刮刑
Once you start it, you can't stop.
一旦开始便无退路
If you give up,
只要你放弃了
your passages will break and you're dead.
立时经脉寸断而死
It's unbearable
这种痛
for humans.
不是人能熬的
I want to give it a try.
我想试试
You're the son of Lord of North Liang.
你身为北椋世子
You're already influential.
已然位高权重
Even if you can't do martial arts,
就算你不会武功
you don't need to take the risk!
你何必冒这种险呢
Old Huang died when he challenged Wang Xianzhi.
老黄挑战王仙芝而死
One day,
总有一天
I'll fight Wang Xianzhi for him.
我要替他再战一场
Only for Jian Jiuhuang?
就为了剑九黄
I don't know
我娘的死
who killed my mother.
凶手未知
In the future,
将来
I'll avenge her by myself.
我要亲手为她报仇
You've made up your mind?
决定了
Yes.
是
You made the choice yourself.
这是你自己选的路
Don't blame me if you die.
死了不能怪我
I won't blame you.
不怪前辈
I ask for that.
是我自己找死
Don't you try to stop him?
你不劝劝他
If I were him, I would make the same choice.
换了我 我也这么选
All right, then.
行行行
Take off your clothes.
把衣服脱了
Sit comfortably.
选个舒服的姿势坐好
Man, stay still.
小子 你坐稳了啊
I'm going to transmit the genuine spirit into your passages.
我现在将真气帮你导入经脉
You have to bear it alone after that.
之后就靠你自己熬了
Thank you, senior.
多谢前辈
Come on.
来
This is just the beginning.
这才刚开始呢
Bear it.
忍着点
Stop the carriage!
停车
Senior.
前辈
You can't help him.
你们帮不了他的
He has to bear
这千刀万剐
the cutting pain.
要他自己扛
It's better than death, anyway.
再疼也比死了强
If you die, you can do nothing.
死了就什么都没了
Why isn't there a sound anymore?
怎么没声了
He's been suffering for such a long time.
疼了那么久
I guess he's too exhausted to yell
怕是喊不出声
or move.
也没力气动了
It's been a couple of hours.
这都几个时辰了
How long must he bear it?
还要熬多久啊
It depends on him.
那得看他自己
What if he can't make it?
那熬不住呢
He'll die, then.
熬不住就得死
Senior,
前辈
if His Highness dies,
世子若死了
guards like us
我们这些护卫
will be dead, too.
怕是都要陪葬
Please save his life.
还请前辈救世子一命
I can't.
没办法
I don't think His Highness can bear it anymore.
我看世子是熬不住了
He has been living a comfortable life.
世子养尊处优
How can he bear such torture?
哪受得了这份折磨
In this case,
事已至此
we'd better consider it for ourselves.
不如想想自己
What's your point?
你想说什么
I worked for North Liang,
我投靠北椋
because I wanted a shelter
一是找个依靠
and I wanted to ask His Lordship
二是跟王爷
for White Emperor Esoterica of Simplicity.
求那本《白帝抱朴诀》
However,
不过投靠归投靠
I never want to die.
我可没打算把命交出去
You're leaving?
你要走
After His Highness dies,
世子一死
who knows how His Lordship will punish us?
谁知道王爷会怎么处置我们
If I leave now,
现在走
I may survive.
兴许还能寻条活路
A deserter will be beheaded.
逃兵当斩首论处
I'm a guard,
我是护卫
not a soldier.
不是军人
General Ning,
宁将军
let her go.
让她去吧
Xu Fengnian can't make it.
徐凤年是熬不过来了
I kindly advise you
我劝你们
to think about the consequence, too.
也想想后果
This is awkward.
这就尴尬了
If only you could leave a bit later!
你说你晚走片刻多好
Please punish me, Your Highness.
请世子治罪
I thought you would run away.
我以为你会逃
Now that you're alive,
既然世子没死
I'll get more benefits
留下来
if I stay.
好处会多一些
You may rise.
起来吧
Your Highness,
世子
we can't keep a girl like her.
这种人留不得
I'll give you White Emperor Esoterica of Simplicity.
我会把那本《白帝抱朴诀》给你
I pledge my life to you, Your Highness.
舒羞愿为世子效死
That's not true.
这就是场面话了
We both know
你我都清楚
that you don't want to die.
你不愿意死
But it doesn't matter.
不过没关系
Not all my subordinates
用人吗
have to die for me.
不一定非要同生共死
North Liang is big.
北椋那么大
There's space for a mere girl.
怎么会容不下一个舒羞
You're as generous as Xu Xiao.
徐骁之后又是世子
North Liang will prosper.
北椋气数当兴
Is there a stream or pool nearby?
这附近有溪流或者水潭吗
There's blood on my clothes.
这衣服都黏上了
It's the invulnerable Kylin Armor?
刀枪不入的麒麟甲
Invulnerable?
什么刀枪不入啊
Miss Hehe cut it
还不是被呵呵姑娘
with only one stroke.
一手刀打成这样
She has strange martial arts.
那丫头功夫诡异
Without the Armor,
要没这套甲
you would have been dead.
你已经死了
Unfortunately, there isn't a second Kylin Armor.
可惜没有第二件了
You no longer need it, anyway.
反正也用不着了
What level is your Dahuangting now?
大黄庭几重了
According to the rule of Wudang,
按武当的功法算
it's the fourth level.
有四重了
How lucky you are!
你真是踩到狗屎了
Even Wang Chonglou has sixth-level Dahuangting only.
王重楼自己也不过六重大黄庭
Are you saying
那这么说
I have to be grateful to Miss Hehe?
我还得谢谢呵呵姑娘
Letting her kill you will be the best token of gratitude.
你把命给她就是谢礼
Senior.
前辈
Am I a master now?
我现在算高手了吗
Not at all.
还不算
But you have great tenacity.
倒是心性还算坚韧
Do you mind
那您考虑不考虑
teaching me some super swordplay?
传我几手上乘剑术
You use blades. Why do you want to learn swordplay?
用刀的非要学剑术
I can do both.
兼容并蓄嘛
It's greedy of you.
贪心不足
This is the swordplay of Snakes in Sleeves.
这就是两袖青蛇
If you can't master it before arriving in Wudi City,
到武帝城之前学不会
you're not destined to have it.
就是跟你无缘
You're teaching me Snakes in Sleeves?
您要把两袖青蛇传给我
Whatever.
传就传呗
You may not master it.
你也未必能学得会
What are you looking at?
看什么
Didn't Lord of Jing'an return your sword to you?
靖安王不是把木马牛还给您了吗
Why are you still using the wooden sword?
怎么还拿着木剑
I threw it away.
我给扔了
You did?
扔了
Why?
为什么
Why do I need a broken sword?
断了的剑拿它做啥
But that's a famous sword.
那可是名剑
Don't you mind?
您舍得
Powerful as I am,
到我这境界
even I use a blunt sword from a blacksmith's shop,
铁匠铺找把钝剑拿着
I'll still be God of Sword.
一样是剑神
How powerful are you?
您什么境界
Without me,
天不生我李淳罡
swordsmanship would be in the dark!
剑道万古如长夜
You're quite boasting.
夸自己夸到这份上
Few people can do that.
世间罕有
I'm modest enough.
已经谦虚了
We've had enough rest.
歇够了
Time to leave.
也该走了
By the way, senior,
对了 前辈
have you thought
您有考虑过
about getting married?
成亲吗
What do you think of Pei Nanwei?
您觉得裴南苇怎么样
Are you out of your mind?
你是在水里泡糊涂了
Seriously,
说真的
Pei Nanwei
这位王妃
is a hot potato.
那可是个烫手山芋
Even Lord of Jing'an thinks she's fishy.
连靖安王都觉得她来历有问题
If we travel with her,
咱们这一路要是带上她
there'll be a lot of trouble.
不知道惹出多少麻烦来
But we can't send her back to Xiangfan.
可又不能把她送回欀樊
If you can marry her,
要是您肯接手的话
you'll keep her under control.
肯定镇得住她
Get lost!
滚蛋
Grandpa Wei.
魏爷爷
Your Highness.
世子
Senior.
前辈
Qingzhou Cavalry
青州骑兵
has caught up.
追来了
It doesn't make sense.
不应该啊
If Lord of Jing'an wanted to kill me,
靖安王要杀我
he needn't have waited until now.
何必等到现在
It's...
是
Young Master Zhao Xun.
世子赵珣
He came for Consort of Jing'an.
为王妃而来
See?
看看
Here comes the trouble.
麻烦来了
Give her to me
把人交出来
and I'll let you leave.
我放你们走
Here we meet again.
又见面了
The wound on your face...
那脸上的伤
Has it recovered?
好了没有啊
Give her to me.
把人交出来
Who?
哪个
You kidnapped Consort of Jing'an.
劫我靖安王妃
You're quite ignoring us.
你视我青州无人吗
How dare you come to stop me
就带这么几个人
with only so few soldiers!
就敢出来拦人
Your father isn't aware, is he?
你爹不知道吧
This is the struggle between Qingzhou and North Liang.
这是我青州与北椋之争
Martial artists shouldn't interfere.
与江湖人士无关
You're scared?
怕了
I ask for a battle assignment.
凤字营请战
I would like to capture him,
愿擒下此人
for your disposal, Your Highness.
交于世子发落
How about this?
要不这样
Let me ask her.
我帮你问问她
If she wants to go with you,
她要是愿意跟你走呢
I'll let her go.
我就放人
You heard us.
你都听见了
Do you want to go back to Xiangfan with Zhao Xun?
想不想跟世子回欀樊
See?
瞧
She doesn't want to leave.
不乐意
How's that possible?
怎么可能
You must have threatened her.
定是你胁迫于她
Stop saying "her".
别她呀 她呀的
She's your stepmother.
论辈分那是你娘
Get ready to fight.
准备冲阵
Your Highness,
世子
I'm sorry.
禄球儿有罪
I'd like to accept any punishment!
千刀万剐
I'm sorry that you've suffered!
世子受苦了
Your Highness.
世子
I'm late.
禄球儿来晚了
let me check on you.
快给禄球儿看看世子
Have you been hurt?
受伤没有啊
Have you barked your skin?
破皮儿没有啊
The monster Chu Lushan has come.
褚禄山这怪物也来了
Li Chungang is around, too.
还有李淳罡
How can I kill my brother-in-law?
这可怎么杀小舅子
Isn't it too hard?
太难了吧
Fengzi Battalion neglected their duty
凤字营失职
and made you hurt.
竟让世子受伤
That's enough.
好了好了
Stand up. Stand up.
起来吧
Your Highness,
世子
who's he?
这谁啊
Son of Lord of Jing'an.
靖安王世子
He came to fight me.
来冲阵的
Good, then.
那敢情好啊
Chu Lushan,
褚禄山
you're a general of sub-third rank.
你身为三品武将
How dare you leave North Liang with your army?
怎敢私自带兵出北椋
He's so nagging.
废话这么多
Shall I kill him?
宰了吧
He's the son of Lord of Jing'an.
人家毕竟也是个世子
We don't have a reason to kill him.
宰了说不过去
It's not a problem.
这好办哪
Let's kill them all.
全宰了
Then let's set a fire
再放把火
and burn their bodies.
烧得个干干净净
Do you hear him?
都听见了
It's not too late to leave now.
你这会走还来得及
When the fight starts,
一会儿打起来
I can't stop him.
我可拦不住他
Your Highness,
世子
Chu Lushan is famous for his ruthlessness.
褚禄山以残暴出名
If we fight directly,
真要骑兵对冲
I'm afraid we can't defeat them.
恐怕难以取胜
I'll take revenge for what happened today!
今日之耻
Let's go back to Xiangfan.
回欀樊
Wait a minute.
等会儿
Don't push it.
你别得寸进尺啊
Give the blade back to me.
刀还我
Go.
走
It's benevolent of you, Your Highness.
还是世子宽仁
In my opinion,
要我说这种货色
we should just kill such guys.
宰了也就宰了
Why did you come?
你怎么来了
Godfather sent me.
义父让我来的
Xu Xiao?
徐骁
Isn't he in the capital?
他不是在京城吗
He asked me to lead my cavalry
义父说有鹞鹰送来剑穗
to Qingzhou for you when I received
我便率本部骑兵
the sword tassel sent by a hawk.
来青州寻世子啊
What hawk?
哪来的鹞鹰
I don't know.
我也不知道
I just saw the hawk that day
反正那天我看见鹞鹰来了
and then I set out.
我就出发了
Luckily, I arrived in time
还好让我赶上
and didn't let them hurt you.
没让世子委屈
Wait.
等会儿
Why did Xu Xiao send you to Qingzhou?
他让你来青州干什么
He didn't tell me the reason.
他没说啊
He simply asked me to take orders from you.
只说让我听世子吩咐
Shall I
要不
go to Wudi City with you?
我随世子去武帝城吧
Ridiculous.
胡闹
What do you think I should do, then?
那世子说我该做些什么呀
Go back to North Liang.
回北椋
I came all the way here.
我这么大老远来的
But you want me to return?
你让我回去了
How about this?
要不
Let them go back
你让他们回去
and let me stay.
我一个人留下
You're a general of sub-third rank.
你是从三品
Qingzhou is the farthest you can reach.
闯青州已经是极限了
If you keep following me, what will the royal family think?
再跟着我京城怎么想
I'll quit my job, then.
那我就辞官喽
Nonsense.
胡扯
Just go away.
赶紧滚蛋
Your Highness.
世子
Shut up.
闭嘴
I came all the way...
你说我这大老远儿的
Wait.
等等
Speaking of it,
这么说起来
I've got a mission for you.
还真有事要交给你办
This is Consort of Jing'an?
这就是靖安王妃
She's indeed beautiful.
是挺水灵的
Escort the two ladies
这两个人
back to North Liang.
你给我送回北椋
If you want to entrust me to Chu Lushan,
把我交给褚禄山
I would rather die.
还不如杀了我
Look what a bad reputation you have.
你瞧瞧你这什么名声
Don't worry, Your Grace.
王妃放心
I've done all kinds of evil things.
虽然我褚禄山什么脏事都做过
But there's an exception.
但唯有一样
I never touch anyone
世子交代过的人
entrusted by His Highness.
打死不碰
Send Qingniao back to my mansion
青鸟送回府上
for a good recuperation.
好好调养
As for Consort of Jing'an...
至于她吗
She has a special status
毕竟身份特殊
and can't be kept in my mansion.
不能留在府里
Shall I find a house
不如我寻个院子
and hide her in Yanzhi County?
把她藏在胭脂郡
Sounds feasible.
倒也可以
But you must keep it secret.
不过得保密
I understand.
禄球儿明白
I'll keep her there without telling anyone.
谁都不说
When you're back, you can have a good time with her.
就等世子回来
What are you talking about?
什么叫我慢慢享用啊
She's my aunt, speaking of seniority.
这位论辈分是我婶婶
That's why I'll keep it secret.
所以我才要保密啊
Don't talk nonsense.
少废话
Just keep an eye on her.
把人看住就行
Aye, Your Highness.
遵命
I know you're keeping a secret.
我知道你身上藏了秘密
After I'm back in North Liang,
等我回了北椋
I'll ask you.
慢慢问你
Your Highness.
世子
You're awake?
你醒了
I'm not going back.
我不回去
But you're wounded.
你身上有伤
I want to travel with you.
青鸟愿随世子同行
Chu Lushan will not go with Xu Fengnian.
褚禄山不会随行
Master?
大师父
Are you going to kill Xu Fengnian personally?
您要亲自出手
I can't show myself.
我不能露面
But if you don't go,
您不出手
who else can kill Xu Fengnian when Li Chungang is around?
还有谁能从李淳罡手上杀徐凤年
Even if I tried,
就算我出手
I might not defeat Li Chungang, either.
也未必能胜过李淳罡
Ah?
啊
What do we do, then?
那可怎么办啊
Among five Fujiang Armors,
如今五具伏将红甲
only the Gold Armor is available.
就剩下一具金甲了
Go to Mount Longhu.
去龙虎山吧
Mount Longhu?
龙虎山
For Four Longhu Arch-Taoists?
找龙虎四天师
Go find the Fisherman
去后山深处
by the Bottomless Pool deep behind the mountain.
无底潭边找钓鱼人
If we want to fight Li Chungang,
要直面李淳罡
we have to depend on the Fisherman.
只有靠这位出手
Is the Fisherman
您说的这个钓鱼人
a great master in isolation?
是隐世高手吗
But without a reason,
可是人家
why would he
好端端的
help me to kill Xu Fengnian?
为什么要帮我杀徐凤年
He's Zhao Huangchao.
他叫赵黄巢
He's also from the royal family.
身上也流着皇室的血脉
Royal family?
皇族
The Xu Family is the biggest obstacle of the royal family.
徐家终究是皇室的心腹大患
If you convince him with this reason,
从这一点说起
he will help you, I guess.
他应该会出手
After Xu Fengnian is killed,
徐凤年一死
I have to aggravate the situation personally
我得亲自在旁推波助澜
so that Xu Xiao will rebel and leave the capital.
才能让徐骁反出京城
When the world is in chaos,
到时天下大乱
you'll have a chance to take over the throne.
你就有了夺取社稷的一线机会
Thank you, Master,
多谢大师父
for racking your brains.
殚心竭虑
No plan can be activated
一切谋划
until Xu Fengnian is killed.
都要从徐凤年之死作为开端
I understand.
我明白
My brother-in-law
这个小舅子
has to be killed.
一定要死
Please take good care of yourself.
您千万保重身体
On your way,
这一路上
if anyone dares to be rude to you,
如果有人对您恶语相向
keep that in mind.
您都记着
Later, I'll kill them all.
回头我一家家灭门去
How dare you stay that!
这话你都敢说
You're no longer scared of military laws?
你是连军法都不怕了
You're more important than military laws.
您比军法重要
Go take care of another thing.
还有一个事你上上心
Wang Linquan and his family have returned to North Liang.
王林泉一家已经回了北椋
Look after them for me.
你帮我照顾着点
Don't let them feel aggrieved.
别让王家受委屈
Don't worry, Your Highness.
世子放心
Lyu Qiantang died in the reeds.
吕钱塘战死在芦苇荡
Here are his cremains.
这是他的骨灰
Take them back to North Liang, too.
你也帮我带回北椋
Find out where the Lin Family settled down.
找找林家最后安家在何处
Before his death, he said
他临死前说
that he wanted his cremains to be cast into the river.
想把自己的尸骨撒在江里
But I believe he wants to go home.
但我觉得他还是想回家的
Take him back home.
让他回家吧
Count on me.
我一定办好
Take care, Your Highness!
世子保重
How far has Yu Youwei gone?
鱼幼薇到哪了
Not far ahead of us.
就在前方不远
Let's go and meet her
咱们先去找鱼幼薇会合
before we keep going east.
再继续东行
Yes.
是
Look at you.
你啊
I was just dizzy.
一时气血不平
I feel much better after some sleep.
睡了一会儿已经好多了
Your Highness,
世子
I can still drive the carriage.
我还可以驾车的
Don't talk nonsense.
别废话
Sit here for recuperation.
好好养着
Where are we going?
下一站去哪儿
Jiangnan. [*Jiangnan: south of the Yangtze River]
江南
I'm going to see my eldest sister.
去见我大姐
Chu Lushan was sent by Xu Xiao, right?
褚禄山是徐骁派来的吧
Yes.
是
He came right in time.
来得还够巧的
I thought I didn't choose the way Xu Xiao arranged for me.
我以为自己没选他给的路
But in the end,
但是到头来
I've been doing everything
我的一举一动
in the way he expected.
还是在他意料之中
He's your father, after all.
那是你爹啊
No one else in this world knows more about you than him.
天底下没有比他更了解你的
He has arranged the future for you.
他给你织的网啊
You can't get away.
你逃不掉的
Here we go.
出发